# Summary

Inspired by the Digital World, since 2008 I have been helping companies to build winning solutions and stand out from the competition. With a solid background that goes from visual and graphic design to frontend development, I create human-centric digital services focused on enhanced experiences.

From a strategic perspective, in the past couple of years, I have mastered my Product Designer skills by ensuring agile deliveries while incorporating Design Thinking techniques to match organizational requirements.

• Design Thinking approach into Digital Projects to match business strategies;

#### Main duties

- Development of solutions based in Design Sprint, Prototypes, User Journey and UX Research
- UX and UI to lead and improve new web products;

Check out my portfolio douglasnonato.com

# Main Skills

- Design Thinking
- User Experience
- UX Research
- User Journey
- User Interface (Figma)
- Product Strategy
- Project Management
- Product Discovery
- Data Analysis

- SaaS
- Responsive Web Design
- Design Sprint
- WordPress
- Agile Methodologies
- Rapid Prototyping
- Front-End (HTML CSS JS)
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Motion Design

# Career history

#### SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

Sebrae 09/2018 - Present For more than four decades, Sebrae has been present throughout Brazil, acting as a stimulating agent of entrepreneurship, helping in the competitiveness and sustainability of small enterprises, through training courses and partnerships with the public and private sectors.

## Responsibilities:

- Management of digital projects and bidding companies, applying Design Thinking approach to match business strategies;
- Development new services based in Design Sprints, Prototypes, User Journeys, and UX Research;
- UX and UI to lead and improve new web products.
- UX Consulting at Sebrae events, videos, and publications;

#### Main projects I worked on:

- Institution's portal and e-commerce;
- Toolbox Sebrae;
- Mentoring network;
- Digital Community;
- App Meu Sebrae

#### PRODUCT DESIGNER

Beauty Date 07/2015 - 06/2018

Beauty Date's main service is the online booking, which connects customers to salons right in their phone screens, allowing them to book appointments whenever and wherever they want. In 2015 the company received an investment of U\$8 million, and for three years I could help grow the company.

## Responsibilities:

- Lead new product features and improvements to the user experience;
- UX and UI;
- Interaction with marketing and IT team;
- Responsible for the group websites;
- Landing pages for new marketing campaigns;
- Front-end programming;
- Storyboard creation, 2D and 3D animations;
- Code reviwer;

#### WEB AND MOTION DESIGNER

Promova Promoções e Eventos 08/2014 - 07/2015

A company with 23 years of history in promotional marketing, event organizations, relationship actions and endomarketing. It operates at national level with offices in 6 cities in Brazil.

# Responsibilities:

- Analysis of briefings and generation of ideas and concepts for projects;
- Website Development. Layout design and front-end programming;
- Video production for promotional actions of customers, project presentations, concepts, architectural spaces and making-off of internal projects;
- Storyboard creation, 2D and 3D animations, video shooting and soundtrack creation:
- · Contact with customers.

# UI AND UX DESIGNER

QLance

02/2013 - 09/2013

Online platform for management of tournaments and events. Launched in 2013, the system was used by large university events.

#### Responsibilities:

- SaaS UI;
- User Experience;
- Front-end programming.

#### **UI AND UX DESIGNER**

Agenda Beleza 08/2012 - 02/2013

The Agenda Beleza is a business platform for Beauty Services. It allows users to find professionals in the beauty industry and schedule the service. In addition, companies can promote online payment in order to guarantee the customer attendance, returning confidence through a discount.

# Responsibilities:

- SaaS UI;
- User Experience;
- Front-end programming.

# **DESIGNER**Provisuale

07/2009 - 03/2012

Founded in 1996, Provisuale has acted in the services sector as event organizer. Provisuale's main undertaking is Futurecom, the largest and most qualified Telecom, IT and Internet event in Latin America.

#### Responsibilities:

- Development of visual identity of the events;
- Creation and artwork of graphic materials;
- Production of promotional videos;
- · Development of hot site. Layout and front-end programming;
- Participation in the annual planning of the sector and operational planning of the events;
- Development of marketing actions to events;
- Experience with travel in times of events, responsible for management of outsourced personnel and monitoring of materials applications during these periods;
- Contact with suppliers.

# Education, Certifications and Training



Post-graduation

#### **CREATIVE AND ENTREPRENEURIAL ECONOMY / 2020-2021**

FAE Business School

## **PRODUCT DISCOVERY** / 2021

PM3

#### **PRODUCT LEADERSHIP** / 2020

How Bootcamps

#### **DATA ANALYTIC** / 2019-2020

Infinitely

## **SERVICE DESIGN** / 2019

Livework

#### **UX METRICS** / 2019

Mergo

#### **PROJECT MANAGER MOBILE** / 2018

Product Arena

## **PROJECT MANAGER** / 2018

Aldeia Coworking

# **ENGLISH CERTIFICATION** / 2017

TOEFL

# **KANBAN** / 2015

Lean Kanban University

#### **IMMERSIVE ENGLISH COURSE** / 2013

BTC English



Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)

# **GRAPHIC AND PRODUCT DESIGN** / 2008-2012

Faculdades Integradas do Brasil - UniBrasil

**WEB DESIGN** / 2007

Senac